Lorenzo Fabbri

PhD Student

Status: PhD Student at the Barcelona Institute for Global Health

Field: Causal Inference, Epidemiology

Barcelona, Spain

Summary

I am a PhD student at the Barcelona Institute for Global Health (ISGlobal). I work under the supervision of Prof. Martine Vrijheid. My main topic of interest is the use of modern Causal Inference methods to answer questions in the broad field of Environmental Neuroepidemiology. I am also profoundly interested in Open Science and Reproducible Research.

I received my Bachelor's degree in Biotechnology and my Master's degree in Quantitative and Computational Biology. You can find me on Twitter, Bluesky, Mastodon, and GitHub.

Working Experience

PhD Student

Barcelona Institute for Global Health (Barcelona, ES)

2021 - Present

- NA

Student Research Assistant Fellowship

Università della Svizzera italiana (Lugano, CH)

2017 - 2017

- NA

Honors and Awards

Outstanding Abstract by a Student

International Society for Environmental Epidemiology

2022

Publications

10 Fabbri, Lorenzo, Ronan Garlantézec, Karine Audouze, Mariona Bustamante, Ángel Carracedo, Leda Chatzi, Juan Ramón González, et al. 2023. "Childhood Exposure to Non-Persistent Endocrine Disrupting Chemicals and Multi-Omic Profiles: A Panel Study." Environment International, February, 107856. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envint. 2023.107856.

Thiel, Christoph, Henrik Cordes, Lorenzo Fabbri, Hélène Eloise Aschmann, Vanessa Baier, Ines Smit, Francis Atkinson, Lars Mathias Blank, and Lars Kuepfer. 2017. "A Comparative Analysis of Drug-Induced Hepatotoxicity in Clinically Relevant Situations." PLOS Computational Biology 13 (2): e1005280. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1005280.

Conference Presentations

Education

PhD Programme in Biomedicine Universitat Pompeu Fabra (Barcelona, ES) - NA M.Sc. in Quantitative and Computational Biology Università degli Studi di Trento (Trento, IT) - NA M.Sc. Student in Computational Science Università della Svizzera italiana (Lugano, CH) - NA B.Sc. in Biotechnology University of Parma (Parma, IT) 2012 - 2016

Service

Skills